Blood pressure is 120/80 and pulse rate is 92.
Tansiyonu 120'ye 80, nabzı 92.
I'm taking out the bullet now.
Şimdi kurşunu çıkarıyorum.
The bullet is out.
Kurşun çıktı.
Removal complete.
Kurşunu çıkardık.
We're not done yet.
İşimiz daha bitmedi.
We still need to repair the blood vessel walls.
Daha kan damarları duvarlarını onaracağız.
Sutures.
Dikiş.
Yes.
Tabii.
Blood pressure is 128/72 and pulse rate is 88.
Tansiyonu 128'e 72, nabzı da 88.
The anesthesia hasn't worn off yet.
Anestezinin etkisi henüz geçmedi.
Come on.
Hadi.
You've got to keep fighting.
Savaşmayı bırakmamalısın.
Dr. Boyer.
Dr. Boyer.
It looks like your surgery was successful.
Görünüşe göre ameliyatın başarılı geçmiş.
Yes, it went well.
Evet, iyi geçti.
The mayor has died.
Belediye başkanı öldü.
Oh… I'm sorry to hear that.
Bunu duyduğuma üzüldüm.
What?
Ne?
It was you who backed out
Cerrahi ekibimizden ayrılan sendin.
No! It's just the boy came in before the mayor--
Hayır! Başkandan önce bu çocuk geldiği için…
That doesn't matter.
Bunun bir önemi yok.
The problem is that we had to cover for you after you backed out
Asıl sorun iznin olmadan ekipten ayrıldığın için
Listen! I--
Dinleyin, ben…
You disrupted the teamwork.
Ekip çalışmasını bozdun.
I told you to do the mayor's surgery
Müdürün emrini dinleyip
according to the Director's order.
başkanın ameliyatına girmeni söylemiştim
However, you ignored the order.
ama sen emri dinlemedin.
But Chief! I was--
Ama başkanım, ben…
A surgical operation can only succeed with trust between all team members.
Ameliyatlar anca tüm ekip üyeleri arasında
You were not a team player.
Ekibe karşı geldin.
I have already reported to the Director.
Bunu müdüre bildirdim bile.
This incident has harmed our hospital's authority,
Bu olay hastanemizin itibarını zedeledi
and the Director is very disappointed.
ve müdür büyük hayal kırıklığı yaşadı.
Prepare yourself for consequences.
Sonuçlarına kendini hazırla.
Uh… Wait!
Durun!
Please wait!
Lütfen durun!
Dr. Tenma, the boy's blood pressure is 114/82.
Dr. Tenma, çocuğun tansiyonu 114'e 82.
His pulse rate is 84, and his vital signs are all very stable.
Nabzı 84, hayati bulguları son derece stabil.
Really? That's good.
Gerçekten mi? Güzel.
Um… The surgery earlier was truly amazing.
Şey, ameliyat tek kelimeyle harikaydı.
Mayor Roedecker, who collapsed at the retreat,
İnziva sırasında bayılan Belediye Başkanı Roedecker
passed away in the hospital earlier.
bugün erken saatlerde hastanede vefat etti.
Many citizens have heard the sad news
Pek çok vatandaş üzücü haberi duyup
and brought flowers to the city hall.
şehir merkezine çiçekler bıraktı.
They are all there to pay respect to the late mayor.
Merhum başkana saygılarını sunmak için toplandılar.
The Eisler Memorial Hospital, where the mayor was operated on,
Başkanın ameliyat edildiği Eisler Memorial Hastanesi
has just held a press conference.
bir basın açıklaması düzenledi.
Mayor Roedecker's cause of death is
Belediye Başkanı Roedecker'ın ölüm sebebi
acute stroke caused by internal carotid artery occlusion.
karotis arter oklüzyonu kaynaklı akut felç.
Despite our best efforts,
Tüm çabalarımıza rağmen
the swelling was unfortunately far too great.
şişme ne yazık ki fazla ilerlemişti.
The city office says it will begin working out
Belediye en hızlı biçimde makamı doldurma planı
the succession plan as soon as possible…
yapacaklarını belirtti…
I have to sleep…
Uyumam lazım.
Next is the news about the murder of Mr. and Mrs. Liebert late last night.
Sonraki haberimiz Bay ve Bayan Liebert'in dün gece öldürülmesi.
As there were signs that the room was ransacked, a robbery is suspected.
Odalarının yağmalandığına dair izler olduğundan hırsızlık şüphesi var.
as they were currently seeking asylum.
siyasi terörizm ihtimali de bulunuyor.
The police are investigating both possibilities.
Polis iki olasılığı da soruşturuyor.
Their son was shot in the head.
Oğulları başından vuruldu.
Although his surgery was successful,
Ameliyatı başarılı geçse de
he is still unconscious and in critical condition.
bilinci hâlâ kapalı ve hayati durumu devam ediyor.
Next is weather news. Sun is expected for the whole country…
Sırada hava durumu var. Ülke genelinde güneşli hava…
I wonder what will happen to that boy…
Acaba o çocuğa ne olacak?
I don't know what'll happen to me either.
Bana ne olacağını da bilmiyorum.
Mr. Reinhart in the ICU said
Yoğun bakımdaki Bay Reinhart
that he can't sleep at all.
hiç uyuyamadığını söyledi.
Can we prescribe some sleeping pills for him?
Ona uyku hapı yazabilir miyiz?
Dr. Tenma, are you listening?
Dr. Tenma, dinliyor musunuz?
Give him a tablet of Halcion.
Ona Halcion verin.
He's been like this all day. I can't believe it.
Tüm gün böyleydi. İnanamıyorum.
-Hey. -Oh.
Selam.
Dr. Becker.
Dr. Becker.
Things aren't going well for you, huh?
İşler yolunda gitmiyor demek.
Did the Director penalize you?
Müdür sana ceza mı verdi?
I told you already. It's all politics in the hospital.
Söyledim ya. Hastane siyasetten ibaret.
If you played your cards right,
Kartlarını doğru oynasaydın
you could have had great success in the future.
gelecekte çok başarılı olabilirdin.
I suppose you will join my side from now on.
Sanırım şu andan itibaren bana katılacaksın.
Don't be so down.
O kadar üzülme.
You will get your chance to redeem yourself somehow.
Kendini bir şekilde affettirme şansın olur.
Let's get some drinks and relax!
Hadi bir şeyler içip keyfimize bakalım.
Excuse me?
Pardon.
I am here to question
İkiz kız kardeşleri
the twin sister.
sorgulamak için geldim.
Detective, now is not the time!
Dedektif, şu an sırası değil.
She's missing from her room!
Odasından kaybolmuş.
What?
Ne?
She walks out of her room and wanders about the hospital.
Odasından çıkıp hastaneyi dolaşırdı.
Ki…
Öl…
Kill…
Öldür…
Kill.
Öldür.
Eisler Memorial Hospital has become a well-recognized
Eisler Memorial Hastanesi bu ülkenin çok tanınan,
and a leading medical facility in this country.
öncü bir tıp merkezi hâline geldi.
It is all because of the excellent doctors here today.
Hepsini bugün aramızdaki harika doktorlara borçluyuz.
I'd like to extend my gratitude.
Minnetlerimi sunmak isterim.
It's unfortunate that the mayor passed away in our hospital last night.
Belediye başkanının dün gece hastanemizde vefat etmesi üzücü bir olay
But we did everything we could as usual.
ancak her zamanki gibi biz elimizden geleni yaptık.
Thankfully, the public has not changed their perception of the hospital.
Neyse ki hastanemizin halkın nezdinde itibarı hiç değişmedi.
Here are the doctors who did everything to save the mayor,
Başkanı kurtarmak için elinden geleni yapan doktorlar burada;
Dr. Boyer and Dr. Eisen.
Dr. Boyer ve Dr. Eisen.
I read your paper!
Makaleni okudum.
Keep up the great work.
Böyle devam.
Director.
Müdür bey.
I… I am very sorry about the other day.
Geçen gün için çok üzgünüm.
Well, it's all in the past.
Artık geçmişte kaldı.
Director.
Müdür bey.
You only did what you thought was right.
Sen doğru bildiğini yaptın.
Director…
Müdür bey…
Next, I would like to ask
Şimdi beyin cerrahisi başkanından bir konuşma yapmasını rica ediyoruz.
Please excuse me. I need to make a speech.
İzninizle, bir konuşma yapmalıyım.
They're not calling you.
Seni takdim etmediler.
What?
Ne?
I'd like to welcome the newly appointed Head,
Alkışlarınızla görevine yeni atanan başkan,
Dr. Boyer.
Dr. Boyer. Bu taraftan lütfen.
Director, what does this…?
Müdür bey, bu da ne…
You can stay in the hospital if you want,
İstersen hastanede kalabilirsin
but you can forget about any promotion as a doctor.
ama doktor olarak terfi almayı aklından çıkar.
I cannot give any chance to someone who causes problems.
Sorun çıkaran birine hiçbir şans veremem.
Your surgical skills are good. That's all.
Cerrah olarak yeteneklisin. Hepsi bu.
You can also give up on publishing any academic papers.
Akademik makale yayımlamayı da artık aklından çıkar.
Director, please wait! I have to talk to you.
Lütfen bekleyin! Sizinle konuşmalıyım.
I won't write any reference letter for you, even if you want to leave.
Gitmek istesen bile senin için referans mektubu yazmam.
You can say goodbye to any ambition.
Tüm hırslarınla vedalaşabilirsin.
The path you had planned as a doctor is no longer possible.
Bir doktor olarak planladığın yol artık kapandı.
Surgery is teamwork.
Ameliyat ekip işidir.
It's only with everyone's effort
Ancak herkesin emeğiyle
that we can save lives.
hayat kurtarabiliriz.
Eva!
Eva.
Eva, can you talk to your father for me?
Eva, benim için babanla konuşabilir misin?
I didn't do anything wrong.
Ben yanlış bir şey yapmadım.
I only followed the order of the patients coming in
Sadece hastaları geliş sıralarına göre ameliyat ettim.
Isn't that the engagement ring?
O, nişan yüzüğü değil mi?
You are so stupid.
Çok aptalsın.
Eva!
Eva!
Dr. Norden! Nice suit.
Dr. Norden, takımın çok güzelmiş.
Enough about me.
Benden bahsetmeyelim.
You're more beautiful than ever tonight.
Bu akşam hiç olmadığın kadar güzelsin.
Isn't this funny?
Çok komik değil mi?
I came to Germany after I read Dr. Heinemann's papers.
Dr. Heinemann'ın makalelerini okuduktan sonra Almanya'ya geldim.
He had taken me under his wing.
Sonra beni kanatları altına aldı.
Now I think of it, the papers that impressed me so much
Şimdi düşününce, beni o kadar etkileyen makaleleri de
must have been written by someone else.
kesin başkaları yazmıştır.
Just like what I had been doing for him.
Benim onun adına yazdığım gibi.
I knew that I was being used by him.
Beni kullandığını biliyordum
But I thought that if I could get to a high position,
ama yüksek bir konuma gelirsem
I could do any research I wanted.
istediğim araştırmayı yapabileceğimi sandım.
We have to advance as academic scholars before we can save lives. Right?
Can kurtarmadan önce
No! A doctor's priority is to save lives!
Hayır! Doktorların önceliği hayat kurtarmaktır!
After all, people's lives aren't created equal.
İnsanların hayatları eşit yaratılmıyor.
No! All lives are created equal!
Hayır! Her can eşit yaratılır!
I didn't do anything wrong.
Ben yanlış bir şey yapmadım.
Is something wrong with me?
Bende bir sorun mu var?
What about you?
Peki sen?
You're not a doctor, just a money-grubber!
Sen doktor değilsin, paragözün tekisin!
A man like that…
Öyle bir adam
is better off dead!
ölse daha iyi!
I should thank you.
Sana teşekkür borçluyum.
Thank you for opening my eyes as a doctor.
Bir doktor olarak gözümü açtığın için teşekkürler.
You've got to live.
Yaşaman gerek.
I lost everything to operate on you.
Seni ameliyat etmek için her şeyimi kaybettim.
I went that far to bring you back to life.
Seni hayata döndürmek için o kadar ileri gittim.
Do you know your name?
Adını biliyor musun?
Your name is Anna Liebert. Isn't it?
Adın Anna Liebert, değil mi?
I told you, Detective.
Söyledim ya dedektif.
She's not ready.
-Henüz hazır değil. -Doktor, bu konuda bir şey yapar mısın?
She did witness her parents being murdered right in front of her.
Ailesi gözleri önünde öldürüldü.
Although she is not injured,
Yaralanmış olmasa da
she is suffering from amnesia due to extreme terror.
aşırı korku yüzünden hafıza kaybı yaşıyor.
Can you delay questioning the girl?
Kızı daha sonra sorgulasanız olmaz mı?
That is going to be hard.
Zor olacak.
The victim is a high-ranking government official from East Germany.
Maktul Doğu Almanya'nın üst düzey bir devlet görevlisi.
If we don't handle this quickly, the guys from the BKA will come.
Bu işi hemen çözmezsek BKA'dan adamlar gelecek.
They always follow close behind
Hep yakından izlerler
We don't have time to take it slow.
Ağırdan alacak vaktimiz yok.
What about this?
Şuna ne dersin?
Let this girl meet her brother.
Kız kardeşiyle görüşsün.
If she feels safe, her memory might come back.
Güvende hissederse hafızası geri gelebilir.
I'm afraid I cannot agree to such an unprofessional method.
Profesyonellikten böyle uzak bir yönteme ne yazık ki katılamam.
Furthermore, Dr. Tenma probably won't give his permission.
Dahası, Dr. Tenma muhtemelen izin vermez.
Tenma?
Tenma mı?
He's Johan's doctor.
Dr. Tenma, Johan'ın doktoru.
What else can I do?
Başka ne yapabilirim?
Hey, Dr. Tenma.
Merhaba Dr. Tenma.
Why are you in a daze?
Neden daldın?
You look pretty exhausted.
Çok yorgun görünüyorsun.
I've been busy with emergency operations.
Acil ameliyatlarla meşguldüm.
I guess they're overworking you now that you're demoted.
Unvanını kaybedince sanırım seni çok yoruyorlar.
No, that's fine. I'm more relieved now.
Hayır, sorun değil. Artık daha rahatım.
Hey, are you alright?
İyi misin sen?
Sorry. I just got paged.
Üzgünüm, çağrı cihazım çaldı.
Are you still going to work when you're so tired?
Bu kadar yorgunken hâlâ çalışacak mısın?
You're only hurting yourself for being so hardworking.
Bu kadar çok çalışarak anca kendine zarar verirsin.
Look at all this, Director.
Şunlara bakın müdür bey.
These are all the presents and letters for him.
Ona gelen hediyeler ve mektuplar.
There is a mountain of them in his sister's room as well.
Kız kardeşinin odası da bunlarla dolu.
Both of their parents have died and they only have each other now,
Anneleri de babaları da öldü. Birbirlerinden başka kimseleri yok.
so the press reported this as a sob story.
Basın bunu acıklı bir olay olarak aktardı.
This is the result.
Sonucu bu.
They can't even pay for the medical bills now.
Ameliyat faturalarını bile ödeyemezler.
This is just troublesome for us.
Bu da bizim için sorun demek.
This tear-jerking story is not bad.
Bu yürek dağlayan hikâye kötü değil.
What?
Ne?
There will be publicity for the hospital.
Hastanenin reklamı yapılır.
That means these kids are still useful to us.
Yani bu çocuklar işimize yarar.
Ye… Yes.
Şey, evet.
How about this?
Şuna ne dersiniz?
We can get the two of them together and take a picture,
İkisini bir araya getirip fotoğraf çekebiliriz.
and then release it to the press.
Sonra da basınla paylaşırız.
The press have been looking for pictures many times already.
Basın şimdiden fotoğraf arıyordur.
Get it done.
Halledin.
Take a photo of the orphaned twins under the great care
Öksüz ikizleri muhteşem hastanemizde
of our excellent hospital.
harika bir tedavi görürken fotoğraflayın.
But the doctor in charge is saying that it's still too early
Ama onlardan sorumlu doktor birbirlerini görmeleri için
Who is the doctor in charge?
Onlardan sorumlu doktor kim?
It's Dr. Tenma.
Dr. Tenma.
Change it.
Değiştirin.
What?
Ne?
There's no need to let that man be in that prominent position.
O adamı böyle önemli bir konuma yerleştirmeye gerek yok.
Get Dr. Tenma off the case.
Dr. Tenma'yı alın.
Uh. Yes.
Peki.
Would you like to try a kind gift from the concerned citizens?
Duyarlı vatandaşların bu hoş hediyesini denemek ister misiniz?
Thank you.
Teşekkürler.
Mrs. Henkel, how are you feeling today?
Bayan Henkel, bugün nasılsınız?
I'm feeling much better because of you.
Sayende çok daha iyi hissediyorum.
Soon we can take out the stitches.
Dikişlerinizi yakında çıkaracağız. Sonra taburcu olabilirsiniz.
I can go home, right?
Eve gidebilirim, değil mi?
But you have to take a lot of rest.
Ama bol bol istirahat etmelisiniz.
Of course, I will.
Elbette ederim.
Give Mrs. Henkel anticonvulsants and antihypertensives regularly--
Bayan Henkel'e düzenli antikonvülsan ve antihipertansif verelim…
Are you okay?
İyi misin?
What's going on?
Neler oluyor?
Dr. Tenma! We let this girl meet with her brother.
Dr. Tenma! Kızı, kardeşiyle görüştürdük.
Then… She screamed so loudly.
Sonra avazı çıktığı kadar bağırdı.
Why did you do that?
Bunu neden yaptınız?
Dr. Tenma?
Dr. Tenma.
-Get her to her room. -Yes.
-Onu odasına götürün. -Tamam.
Dr. Boyer, what are you doing with that camera?
Dr. Boyer, o fotoğraf makinesiyle ne yapıyorsunuz?
I need to capture the moving moment of them meeting,
Etkileyici buluşma anlarını yakalamaya çalışıyorum,
Who gave you permission to do that?
Bunu yapmanıza kim izin verdi?
I'm the doctor in charge.
Sorumlu doktor benim.
You're no longer Johan's doctor.
Artık Johan'ın doktoru sen değilsin.
From today, I'll be his doctor.
Bugünden itibaren ondan ben sorumluyum. Birbirlerini görüşmelerini uygun buldum.
Don't use…
Reklam…
Don't use these kids for publicity!
Reklam için o çocukları kullanma!
It's the Director's order!
Müdürün emri bu.
It'd be better for you to stop defying his orders.
Emirlerine karşı gelmeyi bırakmak senin için iyi olur.
I saved that boy!
O çocuğu ben kurtardım! İyileşene dek onu korumak benim görevim.
You say that, but look at him now.
Öyle diyorsun da şu an ona bak.
As soon as he saw his sister, he held out his hand and cried.
Kardeşini görür görmez elini uzattı ve ağlamaya başladı.
He's conscious and showing good signs.
Bilinci açıldı ve belirtileri iyi.
That means the surgery was very successful.
Yani ameliyat çok başarılı geçmiş.
Thank you, but your work is done.
Teşekkürler ama senin görevin bitti.
Go back to where you should be.
Ait olduğun yere dön.
Damn it! Damn you all!
Lanet olsun! Hepinize lanet olsun!
"Director's order"?
Müdürün emri mi?
"Chief's order"?
Başkanın emri mi?
You're all a bunch of money-grubbers!
Hepiniz paragözsünüz sadece!
Bastards!
Şerefsizler!
I…
Ben…
I didn't do anything wrong.
Ben yanlış bir şey yapmadım.
I'm home, Father.
Ben geldim baba.
Father? Are you in your room?
Baba, odanda mısın?
Chief, are you still here so late? Were you in a meeting?
Başkanım, bu saatte burada mısınız? Toplantınız mı vardı?
Father, are you in bed already?
Baba, şimdiden yattın mı?
I'm coming in.
İçeri geliyorum.
Those guys… are better off dead.
O herifler ölse daha iyi.
Subtitle translation by: Sandy Huang
Alt yazı çevirmeni: Ömür Gencer